Morgan BLEIN

856A 42nd avenue San Francisco, CA 94121 415-230-9012 morganblein@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Programming: Proficiency with Python, Perl, JMP (SAS), SPSS, and SQL (Oracle, Access).

Knowledge of: R, Java, Android, LINUX-UNIX environment, HTML5, CSS3, Shell

scripting, STATA and MATLAB.

Basic Software: Expert with Microsoft office (especially Excel) and Google tools on both Mac and PC.

Video and audio: editing and synthesizing: CS6 suite, final cut pro X, Audacity, FFMPEG.

Languages: French (fluent), English (fluent), Spanish (Basic) and Japanese (Basic).

EDUCATION

MS, Business Analytics

California State University, East Bay, CA

July 2016 (Expected)

Relevant Coursework: Database Management and Applications (SQL), Data Analytics (Python), Data Warehousing, Prescriptive Analytics, Data Mining, Project Management, Marketing Research and analytics, Advanced Applied Econometrics, SAS programming, Big data applications.

BS, Business Administration, Major: Finance

May 2011

University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA

Honors: Honors Cohort Program of 2011, Member of the National Society of Collegiate Scholars Cumulative GPA: 3.58

Relevant Coursework: Quantitative Methods in Business, Quantitative Business Analysis, Analysis of Global Business Conditions, Investment Analysis, Systems in Organization, Financial Institutions & Markets Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Accounting I and II and many finance electives.

EXPERIENCE

Seyyer

Lead System Integrator

November 2012- July 2015

- Managed research teams from Japan, Europe and the bay area to create a first of its kind text to video software application, also creating new age text to speech software.
- Create and sort through internal databases for voices in 3 different languages, and full-facial animation of several actors, blending artificial intelligence and video to create a product.
- Directly working under the CEO, chief architect and VP of products, responsible for demonstration systems for investors or sales meetings.

Market Research Analyst

September 2011- November 2012

- Use of computer analysis systems to program software processing video data collections, examining various facial features for further application with advertising and entertainment.
- Assisted in creating a website by analyzing trend activities and using word processing software to change content or design.
- Perform current social research in order to provide the production team with resources in order for the company to focus on real customer demand
- Conduct market research on how to vitalize this new technology with the "gen Y" using social media channels: YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter.
- Use knowledge of economic trends and investigative studies to assist the company's shift between high-tech research to marketable application.

Sidecar

April 2011-September 2011

Marketing Research Contractor

- Conducted data analysis for the implementation of a rideshare startup in SF.
- Responsible for customer analysis depending on various social, economic and demographic factors in order to build efficient product placement.
- Assisted in creating of the logo, website, name and overall branding of the startup.